Rockbridge Historical Society Biographical Collection RHS.Coll.0033
Washington and Lee University, James G. Leyburn Library Special Collections and Archives
- M-Mc (Box 9, Folder 189-216)
  George Marshall, Bonnie Martin, John Mathews, Mathew F. Maury, Donald McCraig, Ghost McChesney, Thomas Edward McCorkle, McCormick, Cyrus McCormick, Hugh White McCrum, Charles McCulloch Jr., Hunter McDonald, Catherine Feland McDowell, Charles R. McDowell, Ephraim McDowell, McDowell Family, McElroy, William McElwee, Henry McLaughlen, Alexander G. McNutt, MacMillon.
  - Marshall, George (Box 9, Folder 189)
    Marshall, George C. (George Catlett)
  - Martin, Bonnie (Box 9, Folder 190)
    Includes a bound copy of an interview with Bonnie Martin by Eleanor Connor for Lime Kiln Arts, published October 27th, 1994.
    Martin, Bonnie
  - Matthews, John (Box 9, Folder 191)
    Matthews, John, Colonel
  - Maury, Matthew F. (Box 9, Folder 192)
    Maury, Matthew Fontaine
  - McCaig, Donald (Box 9, Folder 193)
    McCaig, Donald
  - McChesney, Ghost (Box 9, Folder 194)
    This folder includes a list of miscellaneous stocks written by McChesney. Written January 20th, 1953.
    McChesney Family
  - McCorkle, Thomas Edward - In Kappa Alpha Journal (Box 9, Folder 195)
    This folder includes a "Kappa Alpha Journal" from March 1935 about Thomas Edward McCorkle.
    McCorkle, Thomas Edward
  - McCormick Family (Box 9, Folder 196)
    McCormick family
  - McCormick, Cyrus - Information Concerning the Reaper and Family Farm (Box 9, Folder 197)
    This folder includes a pamplhet written by T.S. Gillett, published by Weed Parsons and Company in 1855. The pamphlet describes the court case of Cyrus McCormick against William H. Seymour and Dayton S. Morgan.
  - McCormick, Cyrus Hall (Box 9, Folder 198)
    This folder includes a brochure for McCormick Farm, as well as a Pamphlet for the McCormick Celebration, which took place on September 25th, 1931.
  - McCrum, Hugh White (Box 9, Folder 199)
    McCrum, Hugh White
  - McColloch, Charles Jr. (Box 9, Folder 200)
    McCulloch, Charles
  - McDonald, Hunter (Box 9, Folder 201)
    McDonald, Hunter
  - McDowell, Catherine Feland (Box 9, Folder 202)
    McDowell, Catherine Feland
  - McDowell, Charles R. (Box 9, Folder 203)
    McDowell, Charles R.
  - McDowell, Ephraim - Medical Jounrals (Box 9, Folder 204)
    This folder includes a pamphlet entitled "The 'Scotts-Irish' of the Valley of Virginia, and their Influence on Medical Progress in America" by Dr. Hugh Trout, published by Paul B. Hoeber Inc. in 1938. There is also a copy of the Kentucky Medical Journal published in 1933. Furthermore there is a Ephriam McDowell biographical pamphlet.
    McDowell, Ephriam, 1672-1775
  - McDowell, Ephraim - Miscellaneous (Box 9, Folder 205)
    This folder contains a pamphlet entitled "Our Pioneer Heroine of Surgery - Mrs. Jane Todd Crawford" by Mrs. Arthur Thomas McCormack in 1932.
  - McDowell, Ephraim - Newspaper Clippings (Box 9, Folder 206)
  - McDowell, Ephraim - Papers (Box 9, Folder 207)
    This folder includes a bound copy of "Restoration History of the Home of Dr. Ephraim McDowell - Father of Abdominal Surgery: Danville, Kentucky." Published in 2000.
  - McDowell, Ephraim - Photographs and Pictures (Box 9, Folder 208)
    This folder contains three separate silver gellatin photographs from 1957. One is a depiction of McDowell's statue. The other two depict McDowell's grave and location.
  - McDowell Family (Box 9, Folder 209)
    McDowell family
  - McElroy, Lebo (Box 9, Folder 210)
  - McElwee, William (Box 9, Folder 211)
    McElwee, William Meek
  - McLaughlin, Henry (Box 9, Folder 212)
  - McNutt, Alexander G. - Ephemera (Box 9, Folder 213)
  - McNutt, Alexander G. - Newspaper Clippings (Box 9, Folder 214)
  - McNutt, Alexander G. - Correspondence (Box 9, Folder 215)
  - Macmillan - Article on Antiques (Box 9, Folder 216)
    MacMillan, Charles Newton
- Md-Mz (Box 10, Folder 217-238)
  - Miley, Michael - Essay on Photography (Box 10, Folder 217)
    Miley, Michael
  - Miley, Michael - Newspaper Clippings (Box 10, Folder 218)
  - Miley, Michael - Biography (Box 10, Folder 219)
  - Miley, Michael - Notes on Photo Negatives (Box 10, Folder 220)
  - Miley, Michael - Newspaper Clippings (Box 10, Folder 221)
  - Miley, Michael - Capital Stock in Miley Color Photograph Company (Box 10, Folder 222)
    This folder includes a Capital stock for 10,000 dollars in the name of Michael Miley for Miley Colour Photograph Company. Dated 1902.
  - Miley, Michael - Photo Envelope without Photo (Box 10, Folder 223)
  - Miley, Michael - Photo Print Copy (Box 10, Folder 224)
    This folder contains a photocopied image made by Michael Miley entitled "Miley Mosiac." No dates available.
  - Miley, Michael - Documents Concerning Protrait of Robert E. Lee (Box 10, Folder 225)
  - Miley, Michael - Newspaper Clippings (Box 10, Folder 226)
  - Miley, Michael - Copies of Photos (Box 10, Folder 227)
  - Miley, Michael - Business Liscences (Box 10, Folder 228)
    This folder contains two bound scrapbooks of Virginia Licenses issued to Michael Miley as a daguerreotype artist. Dated from 1866 to 1918.
  - Miley, Michael - Newspaper Clipping (Box 10, Folder 229)
  - Miller, William (Box 10, Folder 230)
    Miller, William McElwee
  - Mitchell, William (Box 10, Folder 231)
    This folder includes a list of people who fronted money for the funeral expenses. No dates included.
    Mitchell, William
  - Moore, Andrew (Box 10, Folder 232)
    Moore, Andrew
  - Moore, Elizabeth (Box 10, Folder 233)
    Moore, Elizabeth
  - Morrison, Samuel Brown (Box 10, Folder 234)
    Morrison, Samuel Brown
  - Morrison, William McCutchan (Box 10, Folder 235)
    Morrison, William McCutchan
  - Morrison, William McCutchan (Box 10, Folder 236)
    This folder includes a pamphlet on Reverened William MacCutchen Morrison from June 7th, 1926.
  - Morton, Lucy (Box 10, Folder 237)
    Morton, Lucy
  - Murray, James (Box 10, Folder 238)
    Murray, Joseph James
- N-P, 1 Box (Box 11, Folder 239-272)
  Phil Nunn, Frank Padget, Henry Chester Parsons, Alexander Paxton, Elisha F. Paxton, James John Paxton, John A. Paxton, John H. Paxton, John and Phoebe Paxton, Thomas Paxton, William M. Paxton, Pendleton, Alexander Spotswood Pendleton, Edmund Pendleton, James Dudley Pendleton, William C. Pendleton, William J. Pendleton, William Nelson Pendleton, Frances Penick, Mary Monroe Penick, S. G. Pettigrew, Physicians, William Franklin Pierson, William T. Poague, Miles Poindexter, Thomas Posey, Preston, Randolph Preston, Beatrice Price, Byron D. Pultz.
  Padgett, Frank, ?-1854; Nunn, Philip ("Dixie"), 1866-1938; Paxton, Elisha Franklin; Paxton, James H., 1835-?; Paxton family -- John -- Phoebe; Paxton, Thomas, 1722-1788; Pendleton family; Pendleton, Edmund, Colonel
  - Nunn, Phil (Box 11, Folder 239)
    This folder includes the a photocopy of a portrait of Phil "Old Dixie" Nunn. No dates available.
    Nunn, Philip ("Dixie"), 1866-1938
  - Padget, Frank (Box 11, Folder 240)
    Padgett, Frank, ?-1854
  - Parsons, Henry Chester (Box 11, Folder 241)
    This folder contains a portrait of Henry Chester Parsons dated 1945.
  - Paxton, Alexander (Box 11, Folder 242)
    Paxton, Alexander Sterrett
  - Paxton, Elisha F. (Box 11, Folder 243)
    Paxton, Elisha Franklin
  - Paxton, James John (Box 11, Folder 244)
    This folder contains personal correspondence, journal entries, and a jury summons with James John Paxton dated in the 1850s.
  - Paxton, John H. (Box 11, Folder 245)
    Paxton, John H., Dr., Revered
  - Paxton, John A. (Box 11, Folder 246)
  - Paxton, John and Phoebe (Box 11, Folder 247)
    Paxton, Phoebe Alexander, Mrs.; Paxton, John
  - Paxton, John and Phoebe - Newspaper Clippings (Box 11, Folder 248)
  - Paxton, Thomas (Box 11, Folder 249)
    This folder includes a flyer for the interred body of Thomas Paxton, dated 1788.
    Paxton, Thomas, 1722-1788
  - Paxton, William M. (Box 11, Folder 250)
    This folder includes a photo of W.M. Paxton along with copies of two pieces of writing: "The Covers" and "The Legend of Moaning Falls." Dated 1799.
  - Pendleton Family (Box 11, Folder 251)
    Pendleton family
  - Pendleton, Alexander Spotswood (Box 11, Folder 252)
  - Pendleton, Edmund (Box 11, Folder 253)
    Tompkins, Edmund Pendleton
  - Pendleton, James Dudley (Box 11, Folder 254)
    This folder includes a Cross of Military Service for James Dudley Pendleton dated February 19th, 1890.
    Pendleton, James Dudley
  - Pendleton, William Cecil (Box 11, Folder 255)
    Pendleton, William Cecil
  - Pendleton, William J. (Box 11, Folder 256)
    Pendleton, William J.
  - Pendleton, William Nelson (Box 11, Folder 257)
    This folder contains an in memoriam for Reverend William Nelson Pendleton, the rector of Grace Memorial Church. Dated January 15th, 1883.
    Pendleton, William Nelson
  - Penick, France (Box 11, Folder 258)
    This folder contains a personal correspondence between Frances Penick and J.B. Earman. Dated November 11th, 1897.
    Perkins, Frances
  - Penick, Mary Monroe (Box 11, Folder 259)
    Penick, Mary Monroe
  - Pettigrew, S.G. (Box 11, Folder 260)
    Pettigrew, S.G.
  - Physicians (Box 11, Folder 261)
    This folder includes a number of biographical cards for local physicians in alphabetical order.
  - Physicians - Essay (Box 11, Folder 262)
    Miller, Joseph Lyon, Dr.
  - Pierson, William Franklin (Box 11, Folder 263)
    Pierson, William Franklin
  - Poague, William Thomas (Box 11, Folder 264)
    This folder includes two copies of a biographical report on Colonel William T. Poague, dated 1957.
    Poague, William Thomas, Colonel
  - Poindexter, Miles (Box 11, Folder 265)
    Poindexter, Miles
  - Poindexter, Miles - Correspondence (Box 11, Folder 266)
  - Poindexter, Miles - Newspaper Clippings (Box 11, Folder 267)
  - Posey, Thomas (Box 11, Folder 268)
    Posey, Thomas, General
  - Preston Family - Military Service (Box 11, Folder 269)
    Preston family
  - Preston, Randolph - Essay on Washington and Lee University (Box 11, Folder 270)
    Preston, Randolph
  - Price, Beatrice (Box 11, Folder 271)
    Price, Beatrice
  - Pultz, Byron D. (Box 11, Folder 272)
    Pultz, Byron Deement
- Q-V (Box 12, Folder 273-311)
  James A. Quarles, Read, Andrew Reid, Samuel McDowell Reid, Richardson, Robinson, John Robinson, Eleanor Roosevelt, Pat Robertson, John Ruff, William Ruff, William Henry Ruffner, Schnare, S. M. Schoonmaker, Alfred Chandler Scott, Sellers Family, James Madison Senseney, Abner Terry Sheilds, John Camden Sheilds, Joseph Showalter, John Skinner, Sloan Family, Francis H. Smith, Henry Louis Smith, Beverly Stanard, John R. S. Sterrett, Styles, General Thomas Sumter, John O. Tardy, Lucian Thompson, George Tompkins, John Fulton Tompkins, Harry St. George Tucker, Henry St. George Tucker, Dr. Charles Turner, Sidney Vale
  - Quarles, James A. (Box 12, Folder 273)
    This folder includes two reprints of Christmas sermons delivered by James Quarles. No dates available.
    Quarles, James
  - Read, Beverly M. (Box 12, Folder 274)
    Read, Beverly M., Lieutenant Colonel
  - Reid, Andrew (Box 12, Folder 275)
    Reid, Andrew
  - Reid, Samuel McDowell (Box 12, Folder 276)
    Reid, Samuel McDowell
  - Reid, Samuel McDowell - Photocopies of Correspondence (Box 12, Folder 277)
  - Richardson, Archie (Box 12, Folder 278)
    Richardson, Archie G.
  - Roosevelt, Eleanor (Box 12, Folder 279)
    Roosevelt, Eleanor
  - Robertson, "Pat," or Marion Gordon (Box 12, Folder 280)
    This folder contains Pat Robertson's report card from Lexington High School in 1943-1944.
    Robertson, Pat
  - Robinson, John (Box 12, Folder 281)
    Robinson, John
  - Robinson, Chas J. (Box 12, Folder 282)
    Robinson, Chas J.
  - Ruff, John (Box 12, Folder 283)
    This folder includes a biographical memoir of an "Early 19th Century Citizen - John M. Ruff." Dated December 1987.
    Ruff, John M.
  - Ruff, William Mr. and Mrs. (Box 12, Folder 284)
    Ruff, William White, Reverend
  - Ruffner, William Henry (Box 12, Folder 285)
    This folder contains a bound copy of a biographical report on William Henry Ruffner by Bessie Bare, dated April 10th, 1938. There is a photo included of Ruffner's country home.
    Ruffner, William Henry
  - Ruffner, William Henry - Newspaper and Magazine Clippings (Box 12, Folder 286)
    This folder contains a bound copy of the magazine "The Virginia Teacher," which includes a biographical story on William Ruffner. Dated October, 1924.
  - Schnare, Lester (Box 12, Folder 287)
    Schnare, Lester Llewellyn
  - Schoonmaker, S.M. (Box 12, Folder 288)
    Schoonmaker, S.M., Colonel
  - Scott, Alfred Chandler (Box 12, Folder 289)
  - Sellers Family (Box 12, Folder 290)
    Sellers Family
  - Senseney, James Madison (Box 12, Folder 291)
    Senseney, James Madison
  - Shield, Abner Terry (Box 12, Folder 292)
    Shields, Abner Terry
  - Shields, John Camden (Box 12, Folder 293)
    Shields, John Camden
  - Showalter, Joseph (Box 12, Folder 294)
    Showalter, Joseph
  - Skinner, John (Box 12, Folder 295)
    Skinner, John
  - Sloan, Family (Box 12, Folder 296)
    Sloan Family
  - Smith, Frances Henney (Box 12, Folder 297)
    Smith, Francis Henney, General
  - Smith, Henry Louis (Box 12, Folder 298)
    This folder includes a letter from September 10th, 1934 with Henry Louis Smith's signature.
    Smith, Henry Louis
  - Standard, Beverly (Box 12, Folder 299)
    Standard, Beverly, Private
  - Sterrett, John R.S. (Box 12, Folder 300)
    Sterrett, John Sitlington
  - Styles, Spottswood (Box 12, Folder 301)
    Spottswood, Henry
  - Sumter, Thomas (Box 12, Folder 302)
    Sumter, Thomas, General
  - Tardy, John O. (Box 12, Folder 303)
    This folder contains a photocopy of John Tardy's 1884 teaching certificate for Rockbridge County schools.
    Tardy, John O.
  - Thompson, Lucian (Box 12, Folder 304)
    This folder contains three receipts from the Rockbridge County Court and the sheriff's office in the years 1859, 1862, and 1868.
    Thompson, Lucian
  - Tompkins, George (Box 12, Folder 305)
    This folder contains a large political cartoon from the Birmingham News-Age Herald with a caricature of Rockbridge born soldier, "Big" Sam Dale.
    Tompkins, George Johnson
  - Tompkins, John Fulton (Box 12, Folder 306)
    Tompkins, John Fulton
  - Tucker, Henry "Harry" St. George - Newspaper Clippings (Box 12, Folder 307)
    Tucker, Henry "Harry" St. George, III
  - Tucker, Henry "Harry" St. George - Papers (Box 12, Folder 308)
  - Tucker, Henry St. George - Nomination Speeches State DNC (Box 12, Folder 309)
    This folder includes photocopies of Henry St. George Tucker's nomination speech to the (August) 1888 Democratic National Convention.
  - Turner, Charles (Box 12, Folder 310)
    This folder contains a pamphlet for the memorial service of Charles Turner, held at Washinton and Lee University and dated October 9th, 1999. The folder also includes a commemorative "Five Star General" ribbon, likely from the ceremony.
    Turner, Charles W. (Charles Wilson)
  - Vale, Sidney (Box 12, Folder 311)
    Vale, Sidney
- W-Z (Box 13, Folder 312-339)
  Harrington Waddell, James Waddell, James H. Waddell, Maude Waddell, Ned Waddell, Wade, Wallace, William A. Wallace, William A. A. Wallace, George Washington, William D. Washington, Welsh Familiy, James J. White, Zachariah J. White, Alice Williams, A.H. Williams, Sidney Williams, W. L. Wilson, Winston Family, Mrs. J. B. Wood, Richard Woods, Mrs. Wyatt
  - Waddell, Harrington (Box 13, Folder 312)
    This folder contains a photo of Harrington Waddell from 1943. It also includes two copies of the pamphlet "Four Decades of Progress," which were created for an honorary celebration of Waddell's service to Lexington Schools on May 7th, 1937.
    Waddell, Harrington
  - Waddell, James H. (Box 13, Folder 313)
    This folder includes a research notebook with biographical and geneological background information on many notable Rockbridge County citizens. The author is likely Lyle Letcher Campbell (signed L.L.C.).
    Waddell, James H.
  - Waddell, James H. - Personal Note, April 11, 1884 (Box 13, Folder 314)
    This folder contains a singular letter between Francis H. Smith concerning the funeral of civil war Captain James H. Waddell. Dated April 11th, 1884.
  - Waddell, Maude (Box 13, Folder 315)
    Waddell, Maude
  - Waddell, Ned (Box 13, Folder 316)
    Waddell, Ned
  - Wade, Thomas M. (Box 13, Folder 317)
    Wade, Thomas Morrell, Major
  - Wallace Family (Box 13, Folder 318)
    Wallace family
  - Wallace, William A. "Bigfoot" - Biography (Box 13, Folder 319)
    Wallace, William Alexander Anderson "Bigfoot"
  - Wallace, William A. "Bigfoot" - Newspaper Clippings (Box 13, Folder 320)
  - Wallace, William A. "Bigfoot" - Sketch and Articles (Box 13, Folder 321)
    This folder contains an undated sketch of "Big Foot" Wallace, as well as two photographs depicting his Virginia memorial plaque erected in 1934. One photo is dated 1964, and the other is undated.
  - Wallace, William A. "Bigfoot" - Biography (Box 13, Folder 322)
    This folder contains a bound biographical essay on "Big Foot" Wallace, written and compiled by Harrington Waddell in 1933.
  - Washington, George (Box 13, Folder 323)
    Washington, George
  - Washington, George - Notes on Illness and Death (Box 13, Folder 324)
  - Washington, George - George McGhee on Washington's Trusteeship, 1988 (Box 13, Folder 325)
    This folder includes a copy of George McGhee's 1988 essay "George Washington's Trusteeship over the Estate of the Rev. Dr. Charles Green, 1765-1772, which included the present area of Farmer's Delight Farm, Loudon County, Virginia."
  - Washington, William D. (Box 13, Folder 326)
    Wallace, William D., Colonel
  - Washington, William D. - Newspaper Clippings (Box 13, Folder 327)
  - Washington, William D. - Press Clippings (Box 13, Folder 328)
  - Welsh Family (Box 13, Folder 329)
    Welsh family
  - White, James J. (Box 13, Folder 330)
    White, James J. (James Jones)
  - White, Zacariah J. (Box 13, Folder 331)
    White, Zachariah Johnston
  - Williams, Alice (Box 13, Folder 332)
    Williams, Alice
  - Williams, G.H. (Box 13, Folder 333)
    Williams, G.H.
  - Williamson, Sidney (Box 13, Folder 334)
    Williamson, Sydney B., Colonel
  - Wilson, W.L. (Box 13, Folder 335)
    This folder includes a December 1969 copy of the "Jefferson County Historical Society Magazine," which a piece written on W.L. Wilson inside.
    Wilson, William Lyne
  - Winston Family (Box 13, Folder 336)
    Winston Family
  - Wood, J.B. (Box 13, Folder 337)
    This folder includes a photograph of Mrs. Wood near a variety of Roman memorabilia from 1933.
    Woods, J.B.
  - Woods, Richard (Box 13, Folder 338)
    Woods, Richard
  - Wyatt - Sketchbooks (Box 13, Folder 339)
    This folder contains two undated sketchbooks that owned to Mrs. Wyatt.
    Wyatt Family